A Guide to the William Stanley Braithwaite Collection, 1899-1928, n.d.
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
William Stanley Braithwaite Collection, 1899-1928, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8990
This collection is comprised of 4700 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from Miss Margaret Carpenter of Norfolk, Virginia on September 13, 1968.
Biographical/Historical Information
William Stanley Braithwaite was an African-American poet, critic and anthologist; professor of creative literature at Atlanta University; and a recipient of the Spingarn medal.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains the correspondence of William Stanley Briathwaite, noted black poet, critic, and anthologist, consisting mainly of letters written to Braithwaite in connection with his anthologies.
Contents List
- Manuscripts of William Stanley Braithwaite
  - The Book of Elizabethan Verse 1906 (Box 1)
  - The Book of Restoration Verse 1909 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1913 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1914 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1916 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1917 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1919 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1920 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1925 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1926 (Box 1)
  - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1958, 13 folders. (Box 1-3)
  - The Book of Modern British Verse 1919 (Box 3)
  - "The Great War" 1919 (Box 3)
  - Bay State Book of Verse: 1630-1930 (Box 3)
  - Our Lady's Choir: A Contemporary Anthology of Verse by Catholic Sisters 1931, 3 folders. (Box 4)
  - Material Related to Our Lady's Choir (Box 4)
  - Victory: Celebrated by Thirty-Eight American Poets 1919 (Box 4)
  - "A Note on the Poetry of Mr. Benshimol" (Box 4)
  - Book Reviews in Autograph, There are ten reviews. (Box 4)
  - "The Imagination and Vision of Bliss Carman" (Box 4)
  - Genealogical Background" (Box 4)
  - "William Dean Howells: An Appreciation" (Box 4)
  - "Sophie Jewett" (Box 4)
  - "Lionel Johnson" (Box 4)
  - "The Magazines and the Poets" for 1911 (Box 4)
  - "The New York Public Library" (Box 4)
  - Poems by William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 4)
  - "The Poet as a Man of Action" (Box 4)
  - "Pumpernickel" (Box 4)
  - "The Roots of the Depression" (Box 4)
  - "Sandy Star" (Box 4)
  - "Twenty-Second Summary of the Year in Poetry" (Box 4)
  - "The Art of Charles Dudley Warner" (Box 4)
- Autograph Letters Written by William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Individual folders
  - Folder of Katherine Adams, poet (Box 4)
  - Folder of Frederick Allen, author of "Only Yesterday," etc. (Box 4)
  - Folder of Helen Arnold, former head of Bronte Society in the United States (Box 4)
  - Folder of S. Omar Barker, member of New Mexico State Legislature, 1929 (Box 4)
  - Folder of Katharine Lee Bates, poet (Box 4)
  - Folder of Sylvester Baxter, literary personality of Boston and Commissioner of Parks (Box 4)
  - Folder of J. Oscar Beck, whose book, Windows in Dragon Town, Brimmer published (Box 4)
  - Folder of Lucius Beebe, author (Box 4)
  - Folder of Morris A. Beer, poet (Box 4)
  - Folder of Jane Belfield, author and poet (Box 4)
  - Folder of Henry Bellamann, author (Box 4)
  - Folder of Henry A. Bellows, on staff of The Bellman from 1913 to 1918 (Box 5)
  - Folder of William Rose Benet, poet and critic (Box 5)
  - Folder of Gertrude Ryder Bennett, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Ralph Bergengren, whose book, Gentlemen All and Merry Companions, Brimmer published (Box 5)
  - Folder of John Black, poet and editor (Box 5)
  - Folder of Charles G. Blandon, poet of pen name "Laura Blackman" (Box 5)
  - Folder of Pauline Carrington Bouvé, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Katharine Keats Braithwaite, daughter of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 5)
  - Folder of Benjamin Brawley, African American author (Box 5)
  - Folder of Hershel Brickell, of Henry Holt and Company (Box 5)
  - Folder of Robert Bridges, editor of Scribner's (Box 5)
  - Folder of Amy Bridgman, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Edith Brower, friend of E. A. Robinson (Box 5)
  - Folder of Edmund Brown, of the Four Seas Company, later Bruce Humphries (Box 5)
  - Folder of Ella E. Burbank, grammar school teacher of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 5)
  - Folder of Stanley Burnshaw, editor of "Poetry Folio," in 1926 (Box 5)
  - Folder of Amelia Josephine Burr, poet in the 1913 Anthology (Box 5)
  - Folder of Richard Burton, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Henry Seidel Canby, editor of Saturday Review of Literature (Box 5)
  - Folder of Cass Canfield, editor of Harper's (Box 5)
  - Folder of Harold S. Carew, poet on the staff of Pasadena Star-News in 1923 (Box 5)
  - Folder of Isabel Ward Carter, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Robert Cary, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Katharine Garrison Chapin, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Ralph Cheney, poet and editor of Contemporary Verse (Box 5)
  - Folder of Thomas Caldecott Chubb, poet and author (Box 5)
  - Folder of Thomas C. Clark, on staff of Christian Century (Box 5)
  - Folder of Albert Clements, editor of The Contemporary (Box 5)
  - Folder of Florence Earle Coates, poet in the 1913 Anthology (Box 5)
  - Folder of Grace Stone Coates, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Mary Esther Cobb, whose book William Stanley Braithwaite sponsored (Box 5)
  - Folder of Catherine Cate Coblentz, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Grant Code, poet and author "When the Fates Decree," published by Brimmer (Box 5)
  - Folder of Katherine Hunter Coe, author (Box 5)
  - Folder of Robert P. Tristram Coffin, poet and critic (Box 5)
  - Folder of Lincoln Colcord, poet and author of sea stories (Box 5)
  - Folder of Ruth E. Colman, artist who did charcoal portraits of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 5)
  - Folder of Padraic Colum, poet and author (Box 5)
  - Folder of Isabel Fiske Conant, poet whose book was published by Brimmer (Box 5)
  - Folder of Howard Willard Cook, an editor with moffat, Yard, and C?, author of "Our Poets of Today" (Box 5)
  - Folder of Le Baron Cooke, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Bert Cooksley, poet (Box 5)
  - Folder of Charles Townsend Copeland, Harvard University ("Copey") (Box 5)
  - Folder of Cora, an early friend of William Stanley Braithwaite in Newport (Box 5)
  - Folder of Alfred A. Cowles, Russel A. Cowles and Roger Cowles, poets and early friends of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 6)
  - Folder of James Gould Cozzens, Pulitzer Prize novelist (Box 6)
  - Folder of Nelson Antrim Crawford, poet and editor (Box 6)
  - Folder of Thomas A. Daly, poet (Box 6)
  - Folder of Olive Tilford Dargan, poet and novelist (Box 6)
  - Folder of Winifred Davidson, poet (Box 6)
  - Folder of Mary Carolyn Davies, poet and novelist (Box 6)
  - Folder of Julia Johnson Davis, poet (Box 6)
  - Folder of Miriam Allen de Ford, poet (Box 6)
  - Folder of Floyd Dell, poet, novelist, editor (Box 6)
  - Folder of Frank C. Dodd, of Dodd, Mead and Company (Box 6)
  - Folder of Glen Ward Dresbach, poet (Box 6)
  - Folder of William C. Drouet, friend (lawyer) of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 6)
  - Folder of W.E.B. DuBois, African American author (Box 6)
  - Folder of Sophie Hageman Duckworth, who wrote the first book published by Brimmer, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Folder of Leslie Dykstra, poet (Box 6)
  - Folder of Edwin Francis Edgett, literary editor of The Boston Transori, author, drama critic, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Folder of Sister Edwardine, Catholic poet (Box 6)
  - Folder of George Elliston, Cincinnati poet, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Folder of J. Berg Esenwein, Editor of Lippincott's Monthly (Box 7)
  - Folder of Sister M. Eulalia, poet (Box 7)
  - Folder of Abbie Huston Evans, poet (Box 7)
  - Folder of John Farrar, editor from Farra, Straus and Company (Box 7)
  - Folder of James Waldo Fawcett, author (Box 7)
  - Folder of Sara Bard Field, Woman's Suffrage leader, and Charles Erskine Scott Wood, her husband, poet and satirist (Box 7)
  - Folder of Dorothy Canfield Fisher, author (Box 7)
  - Folder of Mahlon Leonard Fisher, poet noted for his sonnets (Box 7)
  - Folder of Dudley Fitts, auther and teacher (Box 7)
  - Folder of Helen Harnkess Flanders, poet (Box 7)
  - Folder of Jeanne Robert Foster, poet and artist (Box 7)
  - Folder of Agnes Lee Freer, poet in the 1913 Anthology (Box 7)
  - Folder of Robert Frothingham, editor of a collection of adventure verse with Houghton Mifflin (Box 7)
  - Folder of Claire and Joy Gerbaulet, sisters, writers, and friends of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 7)
  - Folder of Clifford Gessler, poet and author (Box 7)
  - Folder of Charles Gibson, poet who wrote "The Wound of Eros," which Braithwaite reviewd (Box 7)
  - Folder of Roy Rolfe Gilson, early friend of William Stanley Braithwaite and Witter Bynne (Box 7)
  - Folder of Caroline Giltinan, poet (Box 7)
  - Folder of Louis Ginsberg, poet (Box 7)
  - Folder of (Box 7)
  - Folder of Vere Goldthwaite, lawyer, early friend of William Stanley Braithwaite, and married to singer Ellen Beach Yaw (Box 7)
  - Folder of Laurence Gomme, friend of William Stanley Braithwaite who published some of the anthologies (Box 7)
  - Folder of Victoria Drummond Goodspeed, early friend of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 7)
  - Folder of Armistead C. Gordon, Jr., who taught at the University of Virginia and edited Virginia Writers of Fugitive Verse (Box 7)
  - Folder of Maude Gordon-Roby, poet and psychologist (Box 8)
  - Folder of Herbert S. Gorman, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Joseph F. Gould, an early friend (Box 8)
  - Folder of Agnes Kendrick Gray, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Philip H. Gray, Jr., once a poet, now a college professor, the 1927 Anthology was dedicated to him (Box 8)
  - Folder of Ferris Greenslet, an editor with Houghton Mifflin (Box 8)
  - Folder of William Griffith, poet and formet president of PSA (Box 8)
  - Folder of Louise Guyol, on the staff of Boston Transcript, whose book Brimmer published (Box 8)
  - Folder of Hermann Hagedorn, poet and author who write biography of Edwin A. Robinson (Box 8)
  - Folder of Molly Anderson Haley, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Anne Hamilton, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Alfred Harcourt, of Harcourt, Brace and Howe, Incorporated (Box 8)
  - Folder of Ruth Guthrie Harding, poet and wife of Richard Burton, in the 1913 Anthology (Box 8)
  - Folder of George W. Harrington, author of book by Brimmer (Box 8)
  - Folder of Mark Harris, author of The City of Discontent, etc. (Box 8)
  - Folder of R. P. Harris, editor of The Archive(Duke);, poet and newspaper writer (Box 8)
  - Folder of Henry Harrison, poet and publisher of Poetry World (Box 8)
  - Folder of Sara Henderson Hay, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of John Russell Hayes, poet and librarian at Swarthmore (Box 8)
  - Folder of Arthur Hayward, who wrote Colonial Lighting, published by Brimmer (Box 8)
  - Folder of Cloyd Head, husband of Eunice Tietjens (Box 8)
  - Folder of Elizabeth Sewall Hill, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Frank Ernest Hill, poet, author and Columbia professor (Box 8)
  - Folder of Caroline Hillman, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Gordon Hillman, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Robert Hillyet, poet, author and college teacher, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Folder of C. B. Hogan, roommate of Philip Gray at Yale who wrote a book on E. A. Robinson (Box 8)
  - Folder of Raymond Holden, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of John Holmes, poet and Professor at Tufts (Box 8)
  - Folder of Roland Holt of Henry Holt Company (Box 8)
  - Folder of Helen Hoyt, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of E. V. J. Huiginn, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Arthur Crew Inman, who book Brimmer published (Box 8)
  - Folder of Elizabeth Rhodes Jackson, sister-in-law of V. Jackson and wife of Ralph Temple Jackson (architect), whose book Brimmer published (Box 8)
  - Folder of Winifred Virginia Jackson, poet and William Stanley Braithwaite's partner in Brimmer Company (Box 8)
  - Folder of Alexander Javitz, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of J. Willis Jefferies, poet who gave monedy for the 1926 Anthology prizes (Box 8)
  - Folder of Oliver Jenkins, poet (Box 8)
  - Folder of Robert Underwood Johnson, diplomat, editor and poet with Century Magazine from 1909-1913 (Box 9)
  - Folder of Thomas T. Johnston, poet whose book Brimmer published, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Folder of Thomas S. Jones, Jr., poet and friend of William Stanley Braithwaite and Arthur Upson (Box 9)
  - Folder of Sally Bruce Kinsolving, poet (Box 9)
    There is a Sally Bruce Kinsolving Room at Enoch Pratt Library in Baltimore.
  - Folder of Burton Kline, on the Boston Transcript and other papers, a novelist, short story write and close friend of William Stanley Braithwaite, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Folder of Alfred A. Knopf, publisher (Box 9)
  - Folder of Alfred Kreymborg, poet, editor and critic (Box 9)
  - Folder of Oliver La Farge, novelist and anthropologist (Box 9)
  - Folder of Vivian Yeiser Laremore, poet (Box 9)
  - Folder of Harold Strong Latham, author and editor of Macmillan who discovered Margaret Mitchell (Box 9)
  - Folder of Margaret H. Lawless, poet (Box 9)
  - Folder of Louise Ledoux, poet in the 1913 Anthology and one of William Stanley Braithwaite's closest friends (Box 9)
  - Folder of James Lee, an early Newport friend of William Stanley Braithwaite who wanted to pay his expenses to go abroad (in 1899) (Box 9)
  - Folder of Lawrence Lee, poet and college teacher (Box 9)
  - Folder of Sinclair Lewis, novelist (Box 9)
  - Folder of Elias Lieberman, poet and a superintendent with New York Schools (Box 9)
  - Folder of Vachel and Elizabeth Lindsay, a poet and his wife (Box 9)
  - Folder of William Lindsay, author who wrote novel, Backsliders (Box 9)
  - Folder of Joseph W. Lippincott, of the Lippincott Publishing Company (Box 9)
  - Folder of Alain Locke, the first Negro to win a Rhodes scholarship, author and educator at Howard University (Box 9)
  - Folder of Herbert H. Longfellow, poet (Box 9)
  - Folder of George Newell Lovejoy, poet (Box 9)
  - Folder of Benjamin Low, poet (Box 9)
  - Folder of Mrs. Edward McDowell, widow of the musician (Box 9)
  - Folder of Percy MacKaye, poet (Box 9)
  - Folder of Norman Macleod, poet and editor of The Morada(a Review of the Southwest) (Box 9)
  - Folder of John Macrae, of Dutton, Macrae (Box 9)
  - Folder of Frederick R. McCreary, poet (Box 9)
  - Folder of Grace L. Mcquesten, to whom the 1916 Anthology was dedicated, and her daughter Margaret (Box 9)
  - Folder of Mae, last name unknown, an early friend of William Stanley Braithwaite in Newport 1900-1934 (Box 9)
  - Folder of Charles Edward Mann, poet (Box 9)
  - Folder of Dorothea Lawrance Mann, poet and author (Box 9)
  - Folder of Rose Zagnoni Marinoni, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Jeannette Marke, author and poet with Mt. Holyoke (Box 10)
  - Folder of Lionel Marks, husband of Josephine Preston Peabody (Box 10)
  - Folder of Earl Marlatt, poet to whom the 1928 Anthology was dedicated (Box 10)
  - Folder of Edward Marsh, editor of Macmillan (Box 10)
  - Folder of Hermann Ford Martin, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Brander Matthews, author and Columbia University Professor (Box 10)
  - Folder of J. Corson Miller, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Berhta C. Mitchell, one of the owners of Walt Whitman's home (1922) (Box 10)
  - Folder of Ruth Comfort Mitchell, novelist and poet in the 1913 Anthology (Box 10)
  - Folder of Frederic S. Monore, early friend of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 10)
  - Folder of Roselle Mercier Montgomery, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Merrill Moore, poet and psychiatrist (Box 10)
  - Folder of Brookes More, poet with the Cornhill Publishing Company (Box 10)
  - Folder of Christopher Morley, essayist, journalist, novelist and poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of William Morrow, of Morrow publishers (Box 10)
  - Folder of Thomas B. Mosher, publisher of Mosher editions, small volumes of literary work beautifully printed (Box 10)
  - Folder of Louise Chandler Moulton, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Karl E. Mundt, Senator from South Dakota (Box 10)
  - Folder of Benjamin Musser, poet and founder of JAPM (Box 10)
  - Folder of Louise Townsend Nicholl, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Edward J. O'Brien, editor of Best Short Stories annual anthology (Box 10)
  - Folder of Seumas O'Brien, poet in 1913 Anthology (Box 10)
  - Folder of John Myers O'Hara, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of David O'Neil, poet to whom 1917 Anthology was dedicated (Box 10)
  - Folder of Curtis Hidden Page, educator, poet and translator (Box 10)
  - Folder of Maxwell Perkins, editor of Scribner's (Box 10)
  - Folder of Bliss Perry, editor of The Atlantic Monthly (Box 10)
  - Folder of Edward E. Pfeiffer, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Wm. Lyong Phelps, author and Yale Professor (Box 10)
  - Folder of Charles Phillips, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Marie Tello Phillips, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Frances Dickinson Pinder, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Piper family, who sold William Stanley Braithwaite his Arlington Heights home -- Mrs. Piper was was a famous medium (Box 10)
  - Folder of Dawson Powell, author (Box 10)
  - Folder of Harold Pusifer, poet and past president of PSA (Box 10)
  - Folder of Idella Purnell, poet and editor of Palms (Box 10)
  - Folder of Louise Crenshaw Ray, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Cale Young Rice, poet and husband of Kate Wiggins (Box 10)
  - Folder of Alfred E. Richards, professor at N.H. College in Durham (Box 10)
  - Folder of James Riley, poet of the early 1900s (but not James Whitcomb Riley) (Box 10)
  - Folder of Belle McDiarmid Ritchey, whose book of plays, His Blue Serge Suit, was published by Brimmer (Box 10)
  - Folder of Jessie Rittenhouse, poet and critic (Box 10)
  - Folder of Walter Adolphe Roberts, poet and editor of Ainslee's (Box 10)
  - Folder of Anne M. Robinson, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Corinne Roosevelt Robinson (Mrs. Douglas), a poet and sister of Teddy Roosevelt (Box 10)
  - Folder of Donald Fay Robinson, poet whose book Brimmer published (Box 10)
  - Folder of Edwin Arlington Robinson, Pulitzer Prize poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Leighton Rollins, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of E. Merrill Root, poet and teacher (Box 10)
  - Folder of Benjamin Rosenbaum, poet whose book Brimmer published (Box 10)
  - Folder of Carolyn Hale Russ -- Brimmer published her father's Log of a Forty-Niner (Box 10)
  - Folder of Charles Edward Russell, author and journalist (Box 10)
  - Folder of Winifred Russell, poet by pen-name Virginia Stait (Box 10)
  - Folder of Kathryn White Ryan, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Mary Farley Sanborn, poet and mother of Robert Sanborn (Box 10)
  - Folder of Robert Sanborn, poet, later with film work (Box 10)
  - Folder of Louise R. Sargent, friend of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1911-1921 (Box 10)
  - Folder of Whitelaw Saunders, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Eugene F. Saxton, editor of Harper (Box 10)
  - Folder of Julia Moody Schmalz, sister of Henry Vaughan Moody (Box 10)
  - Folder of Howard G. Schmitt, who wrote a book on E. A. Robinson (Box 10)
  - Folder of Clinton Scollard, poet and husband of Jessie Rittenhouse (Box 10)
  - Folder of Jeannette Searight, poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Ellery Sedgwick, editor of The Atlantic Monthly (Box 10)
  - Folder of Mrs. William Sharp, wife of William Sharp (Fiona Macleod) Irish poet (Box 10)
  - Folder of Jay Sigmund, poet whose book, Frescoes, Brimmer published (Box 11)
  - Folder of Chard Powers Smith, poet, novelist, and biographer of Edwin A. Robinson (Box 11)
  - Folder of Virginia Spates, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Woodridge Spears, poet and Professor at Georgetown College, Kentucky (Box 11)
  - Folder of Lillian White Spencer, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Leonora Speyer, Pulitzer Prize poet and President of PSA (Box 11)
  - Folder of Vincent Starrett, author (Box 11)
  - Folder of George Sterling, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Oscar Stern, friend of William Stanley Braithwaite (1916) (Box 11)
  - Folder of Roberta Stiles, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Mildred W. Stillman, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Charles Wharton Stork, poet who taught at the University of Pennsylvania (Box 11)
  - Folder of Muriel Strode, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of A. M. Sullivan, poet and former president of PSA (Box 11)
  - Folder of Edith Tatum, poet associated with Palo Verde, Southwestern poetry magazine (Box 11)
  - Folder of Dwight Taylor, whose book Some Pierrots Come From Behind the Moon, Brimmer published (Box 11)
  - Folder of Paul Tietjens, husband of Eunice Tietjens (first) who wrote music for The Wizard of Oz (Box 11)
  - Folder of Ethel Arnold Tilden, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Elizabeth Weston Timlow, whose book Heart of Monadnock, Brimmer published; she wrote books for girls, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Folder of W. G. Tinckom-Fernandez, friend of William Stanley Braithwaite who introduced him and Willard Huntington Wright (Box 11)
  - Folder of Ridgely Torrence, poet on staff of The New Republic (Box 11)
  - Folder of Charles Hanson Towne, poet and literary editor of The Delineator (Box 11)
  - Folder of Albert Edmund Trombly, poet and taught at University of Missouri (Box 11)
  - Folder of Elizabeth Stanley Trotter, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Herbert B. Turner, who published first book by William Stanley Braithwaite, of Herbert B. Turner and Company (Box 11)
  - Folder of Carl Van Doren, author (Box 11)
  - Folder of Charles L. H. Wagner, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Aurelia Ward, early (1901) friend of William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 11)
  - Folder of May Williams Ward, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Nixon Waterman, literary friend of William Stanley Braithwaite who lived in Arlington Heights (1904) (Box 11)
  - Folder of Tessa Sweazy Webb, poet and teacher at Ohio State University (Box 11)
  - Folder of Amos A. Wells, managing editor of The Christian Endeavor (Box 11)
  - Folder of Louis Wetmore, editor of The Book Review( New York Times), 1912 (Box 11)
  - Folder of James Whaler, poet (Box 11)
  - Folder of Dr. Marcus Wheatland, an early friend to whom William Stanley Braithwaite dedicated his Book of Restoration Verse(1909) (Box 12)
  - Folder of John Hall Wheelock, poet and editor at Scribner's (Box 12)
  - Folder of George Faunce Whitcomb, poet (Box 12)
  - Folder of Viola C. White, poet and first woman to win the Yale Series of Younger Poets contest (Box 12)
  - Folder of Mary Brent Whiteside, poet (Box 12)
  - Folder of Marguerite Wilkinson, poet and critic (Box 12)
  - Folder of James Southall Wilson, the Edgar Allen Poe Professor at the University of Virginia, who founded and edited The Virginia Quarterly (Box 12)
  - Folder of Rufus E. Wilson, of the NAACP (Box 12)
  - Folder of William Wilson, an early friend (1902) (Box 12)
  - Folder of Kathryn Worth, poet (Box 12)
  - Folder of Willard Huntington Wright, poet who created S.S. Van Dyne mystery novels (Box 12)
  - Folder of Annette Wynne, poet (Box 12)
- Miscellaneous Material
  - Brimmer Company Ledger (Box 12)
  - Contracts of Authors with Brimmer Company (Box 12)
  - Health Poetry Contest (Judged by William Stanley Braithwaite) (Box 12)
  - Brookes More Poetry Prize of The Granite Monthly(William Stanley Braithwaite) (Box 12)
  - Proofs of some of the anthologies, etc. (All that remains), 3 folders (Box 12-13)
    - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1918, edited William Stanley Braithwaited with autograph corrections 1918, Galley Proof (Box 12)
    - The Story of the Great War, by William Stanley Braithwaite ca. 1919, Galley Proof (Box 12)
    - Yearbook of American Poetry for 1925, edited by William Stanley Briathwaite with autograph notations 1925, Galley Proofs (Box 12)
    - Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1919, edited by William Stanley Braithwaite 1919, Galley Proof (Box 12)